Experience the graphic reality of Death, close-up...
Faces of Death is a horror, documentary film directed by John Alan Schwartz.
A collection of death scenes, ranging from
TV-material to home-made super-8 movies.
The common factor is death by some means.
Dr. Francis B. Gröss, played by Michael Carr.
Self - Cryogenics patient, played by Samuel Berkowitz.
Self - suicide victim shown jumping out of a
window, played by Mary Ellen Brighton.
Leader of Flesh Eating Cult (uncredited), played by John Alan Schwartz.
Self (archive footage) (uncredited), played by Adolf Hitler.
Self, played by Thomas Noguchi.
Faces of Death (later re-released as The Original Faces of Death) is a 1978 American mondo horror film written and
directed by John Alan Schwartz, credited under the pseudonyms "Conan Le Cilaire" and "Alan Black" respectively.
The film, presented as if it were an actual
documentary, centers on pathologist Francis B.
Gröss, played by actor Michael Carr, who presents the viewer with footage
showing different gruesome ways of dying from a variety of sources.
Many scenes were faked for the film, but most portions include
pre-existing video footage of real deaths and its aftermath.
Faces of Death received generally negative reviews, but it was a huge success at
the box office, reportedly grossing over $35 million worldwide.
It gained a cult following and spawned several sequels, the first
of which, Faces of Death II, was released in 1981.
The film explores themes of dying and death, suicide, doomed man, gore, autopsy.
The tone is dark.